<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="plasma_effects">
  <copyright><![CDATA[
    Copyright (C) 2014 Pier Luigi Fiorini

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 2.1 of the License, or
    (at your option) any later version.

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  ]]></copyright>

  <interface name="org_kde_plasma_effects" version="1">
    <enum name="location">
      <entry name="none" value="0"/>
      <entry name="left" value="1"/>
      <entry name="top" value="2"/>
      <entry name="right" value="3"/>
      <entry name="bottom" value="4"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="slide">
      <description summary="slide a surface from a location to another">
        Ask the compositor to move the surface from a location to another
        with a slide animation.

        The from argument provides a clue about where the slide animation
        begins, destination coordinates are specified with x and y.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="from" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_blur_behind_region">
      <description summary="set blur behind region">
        This request sets the region of the surface that will allow to see
        through with a blur effect.

        Pass a null region to disable blur behind.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="region" type="object" interface="wl_region" allow-null="true"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_contrast_region">
      <description summary="set contrast region">
        This request sets the region of the surface with a different
        contrast.

        Pass a null region to disable this effect.

        When a null region is passed the contrast, intensity and saturation
        arguments are not taken into account.

        The contrast, intensity and saturation parameters are in
        the 0-255 range.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="region" type="object" interface="wl_region" allow-null="true"/>
      <arg name="contrast" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="intensity" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="saturation" type="uint"/>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
