<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="greenisland">
  <copyright><![CDATA[
    Copyright (C) 2015 Pier Luigi Fiorini

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 2.1 of the License, or
    (at your option) any later version.

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  ]]></copyright>

  <interface name="greenisland_applications" version="1">
    <description summary="track running applications">
      This interface is used by UI modules interested in tracking running applications,
      for example a library that expose the list of running applications to a launcher.
      Only one client can bind this interface at a time.
    </description>

    <event name="registered">
      <description summary="emitted when an application is registered">
        This event is sent when the first window of an application have been created.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string" summary="application identifier"/>
    </event>

    <event name="unregistered">
      <description summary="emitted when an application is unregistered">
        This event is sent when the last window of an application have been closed.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string" summary="application identifier"/>
    </event>

    <event name="focused">
      <description summary="emitted when a window that belongs to an application has focused">
        This event is sent when a window that belongs to an application has focus.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string" summary="application identifier"/>
    </event>

    <event name="unfocused">
      <description summary="emitted when a window that belongs to an application has lost its focus">
        This event is sent when a window that belongs to an application has lost its focus.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string" summary="application identifier"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
